Ednalyn C. De Dios

2430 NW Military Hwy, Apt 1913, San Antonio, Texas 78231 (254) 931-3882 ednalyn.dedios@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Graphic designer and web developer with 17+ years experience in interactive multimedia design, business analysis, information systems management, and nonprofit management. *Fluent in HTML5*, *CSS3, Javascript, PHP, C++, Visual Basic, Actionscript, Java, and Python.* Experienced in social media content creation and developing utility business applications in myriad of programming languages and platforms. Maintains and utilizes a comprehensive knowledge of office applications, database software, and possesses a strong command of the written English language.

Self-taught and life-long learner, and proud veteran of the United States Navy. Currently obsessed with artificial intelligence and deep machine learning.

COMPUTER & TECHNICAL SKILLS

MS Office: Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, OneNote, Publisher, Access, and OneDrive. Google Apps: Docs, Sheets, Forms, Slides, Gmail, Notes, YouTube, and Google Drive. Adobe Creative Cloud: Acrobat Pro, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, Premiere Pro, and Audition. Other: Sublime, NotePad+, Visual Studio, Eclipse IDE, IntelliJ, SQL, NoSQL, Meteor, WordPress, Drupal, Joomla, Github, Remember the Milk, Trello, Evernote. #socialMediaREADY

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance

Web Designer & Developer. March 2007 - Present

- Designed front-end UI/UX and coded back-end modules.
- Designed in several media to include print, web, and video.
- Performed simple to complex programming and development projects.

Aware Central Texas

Chief Information Director, Family Violence Unit Director, Web / Graphic Designer and Developer, Anger Management Instructor, Webmaster, Volunteer Family Coach. December 2009 to March 2017

Chief Information Director

- Designed, planned, and implemented IT program policy and procedures from scratch.
- Provided direction aligned with organization's 5-year strategic plan.
- Overhauled the organization's IT infrastructure.
- Brought the organization to the 21st century with new media marketing.
- Provided continuous specialized training to 70+ staff and volunteers.

Increased productivity of staff members and volunteers by 50%.

Family Violence Unit Director

- Designed, planned, and implemented program policy and procedures from scratch.
- Provided direction aligned with organization's 5-year strategic plan.
- Provided continuous specialized training to 70+ staff and volunteers.
- Conducted agency's "Communication, Boundaries, and Stress" and "Cultural Diversity" trainings.
- Led the program's effectiveness to exponential growth for 4+ years.
- Spearheaded the pilot program off the ground with the help of the AWESOME Belton, Police Department.
- Provided one-on-one direct assistance and support to victims and survivors of domestic violence/abuse.
- Assisted in the survivor's' journey "From crisis to confidence."

Web / Graphic Designer and Developer

- Responsible for the functionality of the website.
- Designed in several media to include print, web, and video.
- Performed simple to complex programming and development projects.

Anger Management Instructor

- Succeeded in increasing participation through voluntary self-referrals and word-of-mouth recommendations from graduates. Received 99% positive feedback from participants.
- Worked under minimal supervision and guidance of the Education Director.
- Helped participants control their anger in a positive, healthy, and non-destructive manner.
- Trained participants on the cognitive restructuring, problem-solving, communication, humor, relaxation, and mindfulness.

Volunteer Family Coach

 Provided one on one support to families that are struggling with daily life stressors, within a home setting.

Fry's Electronics

Customer Service Representative. October 2007 - January 2008

- Customer service.
- Cashier / cash handling; restocking.

United States Navy

Logistics & Supply Chain Manager, Supply Manager, Financial Manager, Warehouse Manager, Inventory Stock Clerk, Material Handler•January 2001 - March 2007

- Reconciled financial listings for five operating budgets worth over \$63 billion.
- Prepared and maintained documents, forms, correspondence, records, reports, and files.
- Operated office machines and software programs for automated data processing.
- Routed and filed forms and messages.
- Maintained requisition logs and controlled inventory.
- Shipping and receiving
- Micro purchases
- Applied regulations to maintain the security of materials and documents.

- Performed routine inventory and upkeep of several storerooms.
- Ordered/restocked mission-critical parts and supplies.
- Operated forklift to convey or hoist shipments from shipping/receiving platform to work or storage area.
- Observed all safety precautions when performing tasks.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Treehouse

Online Technology Education. February 2013 - Present

- Front-End Web Development
- Full Stack Javascript
- Java Development

Udacity

Online Technology Education. August 2017 - Present

Python Programming

Udemy

Online Courses. 2016 - Present

- Getting Started with Podio
- Process Management Certification with Pipefy
- Amazon Web Services, Learning and Implementing AWS
- Windows Server 2012 Administration
- Windows Server 2012 & Linux for Beginners
- Build a Cross-Platform Mobile App with PhoneGap
- Cybersecurity Awareness Training
- Make Your Agile Faster and More Productive
- Basics of Scrum, Agile, and Project Delivery

Google Certified Educator

Google Certification Program. June 2016 - Present

Interactive Multimedia Certification Program

San Diego Community College District. 2008

Harvard School of Business eTraining

Center for Naval Education and Training Online. 2006-2007

First Line Supervisor Leadership Training

Naval Leadership Training Unit. December 2006

Computer Science & Business Administration

Various Colleges & Universities. 2003 - Present

BS Business Administration, University of Phoenix (SOCNAV, concurrent)

BS Computer Science Program, National University (SOCNAV, concurrent)

AS Computer Science Programming, Central Texas College (SOCNAV, concurrent)

AS Computer Science Information Technology, Central Texas College (SOCNAV, concurrent)

AS Computer Science Information Security, Central Texas College (SOCNAV, concurrent)

AS Computer Science Network Systems Administrator, Central Texas College (SOCNAV, concurrent)

AS Computer Science Programming, Central Texas College (SOCNAV, concurrent)

AA General Studies, Central Texas College (SOCNAV, concurrent)

AWARDS & RECOGNITION

- Joint-Service Commendation Medal
- Navy Good Conduct Medal
- Admiral's Letter of Merit
- Sailor of the Year
- Sailor of the Quarter

- Global War on Terrorism Service Medal
- Iraqi Campaign Medal
- Armed Forces Expeditionary Medal
- Enlisted Surface Warfare Specialist
- Enlisted Aviation Warfare Specialist

MISC.

Online Resume: http://ednalyn.com

Online Portfolio & Blog: http://ddfloww.com

• Treehouse Account: https://teamtreehouse.com/ednalyndedios